Hello, everyone. Welcome back to my previous tutorial session. So in this session, I'll
create here the MySQL for the drop database. Okay. And it's the most important operation
or managing your database environment. Okay. So first of all, I can simply explain for
why and what to use for the drop database statement in the MySQL used to do it and existing
database. It's a critical operation. It's essential to understand how it works. Okay.
So now just let's explore with some example. So first of all, I can drop in a simple database.
Okay. So now just go here. First of all,
here I will use the drop the database name, suppose, and previously created the company database
with no longer need. Okay. So first of all, here I can type the drop, then create here,
the type the database, the name for here, the company. Okay. So previous example,
tutorial completely created the database. So now the drop the data. So in this drop database statement,
to delete the company database and the operation and now try to successfully create. So first of all,
I can select and execute and just wait and you can see here, completely just searching here
and here I can just wait for two seconds now. And now you can see here, it will create for the
confirmation message from this operation is completely successful because the MySQL between the
confirmation message indicating that that database has been dropped. Okay. And the next step here,
complete use, now here, create for use the SQL drop database for existing statement. Okay.
So the drop database in existing statement, include a condition to check other database
for trying to delete. Okay. So just open for another query and first of all here,
I can just go to the session and just use for the self-run database and first of all,
here, I can describe this drop for the data base for if. So EX,
existing query now, EX, ISG, exist, and use the database name, suppose like here, the cells.
One, okay. So now here, create into database now, just select and then execute.
And the storage here, that says because currently used, okay. So now just here, checking this inside,
and now just here, I can select the cell, so on. And then I can just remove and just try to
remove here, so just wait and just wait here, few seconds. Now it is perfectly searching here.
Okay. So now you can see here, perfectly create for the message in the drop database for
exist for the cell, so on completely in our drop down. And here is the create a show for the message
for the comment is completely successful, okay. So I hope you understand, and the next step here,
I can just create the multiple database, okay. So first of all here, I can do another new query,
and first of all, I can style this is the, the second type, this is the drop, then
database, name for here, the cells to, and also for here, the cells of tree, okay. So now here,
completely different here, I can just select and execute. So now just select and execute and
perfectly drop for exist to database, okay. So you can see here, create for the message is perfectly
successful, drop these two database. So now to verify, so first of all, I can just
read up now and go for in this inside place for class icon, and now just wait and you can see
here, perfectly removed with cells to under cell C database. And I hope you perfectly understand,
and here in this session, I have completely dropping the database using the MySQL,
with some practical example. So I hope you find this tutorial helpful, stay tuned for more MySQL
tips and tricks, and thank you for watching.